hi folks welcome to ditto Insurance
joining me today is a very familiar face
again Mr Ajay now Ajay here is our
senior program manager and has advised
over 5,000 clients welcome
Ajay I welcomed you but I'm also
disappointed in you with one thing for
what you didn't tell me that there is a
50% discount going in term
insurance discount okay um you must be
mistaken yeah because there is like a
price hike going on right so it's like
you have the complete opposite news no
no no no I I'll tell you I know I read
it right because it said that I can
finish off my premium
payments with 50% discount now why
didn't you tell me about that I think
what you're looking at is the limited
pay options I mean you're probably
prepaying your premiums is that what
what you're talking about yeah but
essentially I'm really paying 50% of
what I would pay now uh as a senior
program manager and and adviser to me
and as a dear friend also yeah why
wouldn't you tell me that this is one
great option that I could get this all
right so let me first give you an
example so that you understand okay
right so say for example you are paying
around 16,000 rupees here early for a 2
CR plan right let's just take your case
like say you're a non-smoker yes 26 yeah
for the viewers who want to know about
him yeah so say you're going for a 2 CR
plan okay right so um you're say your
premiums are probably around 16,000 you
pay for around say 40 years yeah right
which is like the extent of your policy
for around 65 odd years correct so 6.4
lakh correct that's that's that's that's
how much I would be paying You' be
paying right but say like you mentioned
correct okay you just say pay your
premiums for 10 years you pay 35,000 a
year is around just 350,000 exactly so
this is what you're considering as a 50%
discount exactly 50% discount right but
if you look at a concept which is called
as the time value of money okay this is
not really the case okay what is what is
that yeah
so if I am to say give you an option to
get 100 rupes now and 100 rupes a year
later which one would you choose can I
choose
both
um okay let's say I I would take it
now unless you compounding uh 100 and
giving me after one year exactly right
so that is the opportunity cause that
you know you probably would have earned
some more money getting that amount and
also the fact that 100 rupees K I might
get maybe a maybe a Biryani today and
then next year I wouldn't because the
inflation it would have become costlier
I I don't think you'll get a Biryani for
100 now but yeah you definitely would
have gotten it say 10 15 years back
right right so but now that is not
possible correct you see inflation you
know comes into the picture correct
right so the money has time value right
so the amount right now whichever
probably you are paying and the amount
that you're paying like say 30 years
down the line might not be the same go
your premiums okay so 16,000 right now
okay okay might seem like okay I'm I'm
paying a considerable amount right now
okay but I'm paying it for an extended
duration right but the same 16,000 after
say 15 20 years value of that 16,000 is
going to be a significantly lesser bump
on your
pocket yeah I mean 16,000 right now
feels like oh 16,000 correct but say
after 10 years it might feel take it's
not much exactly that's the beauty of
term payments premium right because
they're locked in just months now folks
facts like these are the exact reasons
why you should consider getting a term
insurance when you're young Ajay has
also kept on saying that when you buy a
term insurance when you're young there's
a good possibility of locking in your
premiums for a very little price now if
you're in the market to look for an
insurance then ditto can help you we
just not help you buy but also make you
understand how Insurance works and which
policy is the best for you now what you
can do is head to the description you'll
find a link there now let me remind you
this is not an ordinary link this is a
special link because anyone who goes
through this link we are releasing a
limited slot for our advisers to give
you advises on a special basis now don't
miss this opportunity aay let me get
back to you yeah talking about limited
pay and regular pay I understood that
the time value of money is in the uh
picture but still is there any scenario
where limited pay might make sense there
are a lot of scenarios right so I mean
in pure you know the financial aspect of
it know regular pay might seem you know
quite good right but I have seen a lot
of you know Finance professionals
themselves go for the limited pay okay
right mainly because because of the you
know the convenience factor right so say
for example I'm someone who's a very
high earning like you know professional
okay right I'm probably earning uh you
know good 60 70 lakh or 40 50 lakhs
correct right and I have very less
expenses okay and I'm probably going to
say uh you know start a family soon
right another four five years right I
just want to probably get my premiums
done over it I don't want this kind of
recording expenses understood already my
investments are taken care of correct
right I've already taken care of all the
other things I don't want any recording
expenses coming and I don't want you
know when I'm starting a family these
kind of additional expenses coming as
well so since I have a lot of disposable
income I'm probably going to finish them
off faster understood right I also have
another thing that uh you know even if I
am you know going for uh you know like
say something like entrepreneurship or
an early retirement mhm right so when
I'm earning well I probably want to
finish these off so that while I'm
taking that kind of a risk right I can't
have recurring payments and other things
coming along with probably the amount of
debt and other risks that I'm taking
correct that also increases with the age
so what you're saying that if you're
younger then and if you have some money
lying around then a limited pay would be
a good option yes it is it is okay and
uh who should consider a regular pay M
um who who what's what's the profile in
your mind like see one it is like you
know based on your financial goals right
so that you know at ditto we probably
ask and you know a full understanding of
your profile right so we get to know
about what are the things you have do
you have any loans do you have a lot of
expenses to take care of right so if
you're going to have you know say your
income is 1 lakh and your expense is
probably around that much you probably
aren't going to you know afford a
limited pay and you know forcing you to
go for that doesn't make sense yeah
right so unless you have a good amount
of disposable income and again these
kind of goals like early retirement or
you know entrepreneurship down the line
correct right and you know sometimes
it's just the peace of mind I mean I
know it sounds silly there was this one
person who just said that I know I don't
want to be brooding about death all all
the time and I just want to get done
with the premium so there are an end
number of reasons correct that's right
now uh is and you took a scenario of of
mine you said that uh 16,000 paid for
over 40 years will amount 6.4 lakhs and
if I pay around 35,000 for 10 years
it'll equal to around three and a half
and then I'll still be insured for the 2
CR yeah uh is there only a 10year plan
are there any lesser plans or or more so
there are so many options I mean there
are options to pay for 15 years 10 years
5 years okay I've even seen like you
know companies having a single payment
year option right and within a single
year they pay a lumpsum amount of three
four lakhs and you know get the policy
issued that happens as well I mean now
I'm really considering where they get
their income from yeah that's great so
what you saying is you have a 5e and 10
year 15 year and so on correct okay
understood
great now uh any parting thoughts or
rather let me put that this way what
does dto recommend so like I said you
know we first look at the number of
factors right so based on your profile
the amount of disposable income you have
right so what kind of uh you know like
say if you're currently having a family
what kind of expenses you'll be incoming
based on that we recommend right so if
you do have the you know disposable
income for The Limited pay you can
definitely go for it right I mean a lot
of critics might say that you know
you're not being very Financial you're
not making a prudent decision correct
right but know the math aside you know
it might make sense for you yeah but
again if you're somebody who is barly
able to make up for your expenses and
emis I would definitely suggest go for
regular pay do not you know it should
never cause a financial burden right
because you're buying this for your
peace of mind and if you want to have
ample liquidity to you know take care of
your other expenses do not opt for a
limited pay correct yeah as you saw
folks that there are a lot of factors
that you need to consider if you want to
go in for a regular pay or a limited pay
now if you have considered buying a term
insurance and if you have any doubts
regarding that please feel free to put
them in the comment section below and
Ajay will be answering that now Ajay
thank you so very much for clearing the
air between regular pay and limited pay
and uh sorry for telling that you didn't
tell me about the the discount that's
okay now folks that's it for this
episode and like always if you found
this video helpful drop in a like smash
that subscribe button and as always
happy Insurance hunting